# Thomas William Foley

Accomplished and innovative Senior Business Development Specialist recognized for top sales performance. Reliable project manager with a core understanding of relationship building and implementing a consultative development approach. Hired, trained and supported associate growth, incorporating a variety of motivational techniques. Leader of multiple successful market launches focused on extracting unrealized commercial, industrial and "C-Suite vertical profit margin opportunities.

ThomasWilliamFoley@gmail.com

(914) 924 - 6024

Rockland County, NY

in linkedin.com/in/ThomasWFoley

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

### **Regional Business Development Manager K&B** Acoustics Contracting

04/2019 - Present

Westchester, New York

- Fostered new business relationships with commercial, industrial and private organizations through creative prospecting
- · Acquired 10 new clients within first 6 months of employment
- Achieved new client, new project and new dollar sales objectives: 7 contracted projects totaling \$575,000 in sales
- Grew existing relationships utilizing past successes while positioning our inventive services and solutions
- Created and present turn-key proposals combining rigorous market and competitive research coupled with project goals and timelines
- Managed project logistics and remained the main point of contact through completion

Contact: Kenny Klink - (914) 557-0994

#### **Business Development Executive**

Carr, Riggs & Ingram CPA and Advisory Firm

08/2018 - 04/2019

A Top 20 nationally ranked CPA and advisory firm located in 25+ markets across 10 southeast states

Raleigh, North Carolina

- Established new and grew existing relationships with clients, partners and managers throughout the Southeast region
- Oversaw 5 regions providing training to company Partners on best sales and consulting practices
- Identified new business opportunities by presenting customers with consulting options to lower overhead while increasing financial strength
- Coordinated proposal opportunities and served as the lead for negotiating the closure of new accounts

#### **Director of Business Development** Aris Energy Solutions

05/2016 - 08/2018

A renewable wind energy firm providing enhanced Wind Turbines, Enhanducts and Ventilation Exhaust products in.

Raleigh, North Carolina

- Responsible for establishing Aris Solar, a division of Aris Wind Solutions, budgets, forecasting, hiring and training new associates.
- Developed and implemented entire market penetration plan using a variety of innovative tools and best practices.
- Oversaw company's expansion throughout the Southeast, generating \$1 million in closed sales/revenue within the first sixty days.
- Managed entire project life cycle from sales through project lead overseeing engineering, procurement and construction.

# **Business Development Manager**

Hannah Solar

03/2011 - 05/2016

Charlotte, North Carolina

A full service solar integrator providing the Southeast the best in engineering, installation and service of solar arrays and other renewable energy solutions

- Oversaw company's expansion from Georgia, into North and South Carolina, increasing territory sales from below \$1 million in 2013-2014 to an average of \$4 million a year in 2015 and 2016.
- Responsible for 21% of total company gross sales in 2015.
- Managed entire project life cycle from sales through project lead , overseeing engineering, procurement and construction.
- Directed sales and project meetings, timelines, budgeting, sub-contractor responsibilities and employee performance reporting.

## **EDUCATION**

#### State University at Oneonta Bachelor of Arts

Majors: Psychology and Sociology

Minor: Business Communications